Summary

Designed and engineered complex software for digital photography, financial and VFX markets. Worked in distributed, multilingual and multicultural teams. Solid knowledge in Windows software development requiring high performances (multithreading, concurrency, distributed computing...) and in cloud hosted applications, Well-experienced in Agile methodology (Scrum/Kanban) for different types of projects, Applied Continuous Integration and enforced quality in the projects. Living in Southeast Asia for 5 years (Indonesia, Thailand).

Currently based in Bangkok, willing to relocate.

Fields of expertise: C#, .NET, WPF, .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, C++/CLI, Entity Framework, AOP, Python, Agile methodologies, nUnit/xUnit, TDD, Continuous integration, SQL, HTML/CSS, Javascript, Linux, Docker, Azure (WebApp, Storage, SQL, Containers, ACR, ACI).

Experience

Since Oct. 2010 Senior software engineer

DxO – Photography (Paris – France – On site/Remote)

Developing DxO PhotoLab, the award-winning RAW image processing software. DxO PhotoLab (former DxO OpticsPro) is a desktop application software that automatically corrects optical flaws, extends dynamic range, and seamlessly removes digital noise from images.

In charge of every aspect of the product development following all the best practices: Agile/Scrum, (A)TDD, continuous integration and delivery, automated testing...

Technical environment : .NET 4.7, WPF, C++, C++/CLI, Entity Framework, DirectX, Wix, NSIS, Python, Git, Docker, SQLite, PostSharp, nUnit, Gherkin, Visual Studio 2017, Atlassian Suite (Jira/Bamboo/BitBucket/Confluence), MixPanel, InfluxDB, Grafana

Apr. 2018 – Oct. 2018 Senior software engineer

GSea Design – Engineering (Lorient – France - Remote)

Developed SofiaRemote solution – SofiaRemote is a SaSS solution to run composite structures calculations on the cloud.

In charge of the implementation and deployment of the whole solution including clients applications, brokers, databases, processing servers...

Technical environment: .NET Core, ASP.NET Core, Entity Framework, RabbitMQ, Docker, REST API, DevExpress, Azure, MS SQL Server, xUnit, VSTS (source control and Continuous Integration), HTML/CSS (Bootstrap), Stripe payment, Typescript



Grégoire Pailler Crosscreek 7A 10/2 Ekamai road 10110 Bangkok Thailand

gregoire@pailler.fr +66.97.009.8492 +33.6.76.41.96.82

> French 35 years old



May 2010 - Oct. 2010

Senior software engineer

Ullink – Financial services (Paris – France)

Developed UL Trader – UL Trader is a multi-asset trading frontend for an Order Management System.

Technical environment : C#, .NET, WinForms, DevExpress, Java, IKVM, Atlassian Jira, Jenkins, CVS, SVN

<u>Dec. 2004 – Apr. 2010</u> R&D software developer

Def2Shoot – Motion pictures and film (Paris – France)

Developed FOAM, an integrated tool to manage the whole production pipeline of post-production studios.

In charge of the development of:

- an asset management tool
- a file management tool (version tracking, storage virtualization...)
- a project management tool (task management, workflow definition ...)
- a real time high definition image sequence player and color checking system
- a network rendering management system (for Maya, XSI, Fusion...)

Technical environment : C#, .NET, WinForms, DevExpress, C++/CLI, PostgreSQL, SVN, AutoDesk products (3DSMax, Maya, SoftImage | XSI), CruiseControl

<u>Apr. 2002 – Aug. 2005</u> Software developer / Director AllCore – Consulting (Lyon – France)

Software development for various clients (websites, desktop softwares...)

Education

Jun. 2001

Baccalauréat, science major (French high-school degree)

Additional

Languages

French – Native / English – Proficient / Bahasa Indonesia - Conversational

Open source projects (owner or main contributor)

MegaApiClient : mega.nz client library (C# / ≈ 50.000 downloads on Nuget) https://github.com/gpailler/MegaApiClient

SlackAPI : Slack API wrapper (C# / ≈ 60.000 downloads on Nuget) https://github.com/Inumedia/SlackAPI

AtlassianBot: Slack integration for Atlassian tools (Python) https://github.com/gpailler/AtlassianBot

tPresent : Remote presence for distributed teams (Python) https://github.com/gpailler/tPresent Resum



